Guide to the Backus Historical Society Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
Backus Historical Society Records
1853-1961
RG 306
Yale University Divinity School Library
2.5
(3 boxes)
The Backus Historical Society Records, 1853-1961, are primarily records of administration and documentation of library accessions. In addition, there is a group of material identified as Collected Papers, although there is no record to verify provenance of these manuscripts.
Backus Historical Society (Newton, Mass.)
Biographical / Historical
The Backus Historical Society was organized March 10, 1853, with a mandate "to collect and to preserve by publication or otherwise materials illustrative of the history of Baptist churches." Early work of the Society revolved around annual meetings at which papers were presented for discussion and the republication of Isaac Backus' A History of New England, with Particular Reference to the Denomination called Baptists. However, later concerns of the Society revolved around the growing collection of books, pamphlets and manuscripts.
In 1865 the Library was moved to Colby Hall on the campus of Newton Theological Institution, and later moved again to the new Hills Library at Newton. Records of the early 1900s show increasing concern of the members regarding the care and preservation of the library collection. Interest in moving the Library to Boston where the collection would be in proximity to the Congregational Library resulted in negotiations with trustees of the Ford Memorial Building and a move to that site. It became evident that a full-time librarian was needed to properly maintain the Library; so in 1907 the Society and the American Baptist Missionary Union hired Arthur W. Smith as librarian, and shared the expense of his salary.
Largely because of the work of Smith, the New England Baptist Library Association was formed in 1908. The Backus Historical Society, American Baptist Missionary Union, Woman's Baptist Foreign Missionary Society and Boston Baptist Social Union were corporate members which deposited library collections in a single facility, but retained ownership of the material. The Society's Library became known as the Backus Collection of New England Baptist Library. This arrangement was satisfactory for approximately the next 20 years; and once again the Society's interest focused on discussion of papers presented at meetings. However, the affiliation of Andover Theological Seminary and Newton Theological Institution resulted in discussion of reorganization and in 1931 the Society voted to move its Library to Andover Harvard Theological Library, Harvard Divinity School, to establish a collection of Baptist material there. The Library was moved to Cambridge in 1932 and in 1934 the Society voted to separate from New England Baptist Library Association and to affiliate with Newton.
The 1934 vote above was the last record of the Society until a meeting in 1952. The Society's work was revived in the familiar form of annual meetings and the presentation of papers for discussion. The last meeting of record was May 2, 1961; there is no reference to a decision to dissolve the corporation. There is no reference in Society records to the transfer of the Library to Andover Newton Theological School.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Andover Newton Theological School, 2017
Scope and Contents
The Backus Historical Society Records, 1853-1961, are primarily records of administration of the Society and documentation of its library accessions. Records organized in the Library series include a group of material identified as Collected Papers; there is no record to verify provenance of these manuscripts. The Isaac Backus Papers (now RG 280) were owned by the Society; and these Collected Papers were filed with the Backus Papers. When the Backus Papers were cataloged by Andover Newton Theological School library staff, manuscripts postdating the life of Isaac Backus were removed and placed with the Society's records.
The Collected Papers are arranged chronologically. There are two significant groups of manuscripts filed in this chronology: correspondence of Irah Chase and correspondence of the secretary of Massachusetts Baptist Missionary Society (predecessor organization of The American Baptist Churches of Massachusetts/TABCOM). The remaining manuscripts are primarily letters, autobiographical statements and church historical sketches.
The records have been kept in the order described in the finding aid originally prepared by Andover Newton Theological School library staff, with some unorganized material added at the end.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in six series:
I. Legal Records
II. Administrative Records
III. Ad Hoc Committees
IV. Papers Read to the Society
V. Library
VI. Added Material
Backus Historical Society (Newton, Mass.)
- Legal Records, Series I
  - Constitution, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agreement between the Backus Historical Society and the American Baptist Missionary Union, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Administrative Records, Series II
  - Secretary
    - Minute book, includes constitutions and membership lists, 1853 March 10–1962 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Membership lists, 1907-1908, no date (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Applications for membership, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - List of officers, 1853-1907 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1912, no date (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Notes, circular regarding Backus Historical Society, 1907-1908, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Treasurer
    - Annual reports, 1859, 1894, 1896-1908, 1955, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Account book, 1893-1912, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Receipts (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Librarian
    - Annual reports, 1859, 1892, 1894-1912, no date (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Ad Hoc Committees, Series III
  - Report of Committee to negotiate with the Trustees of the Ford building, 1905 October 16 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Report of Committee on enlargement of funds, 1907 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Papers Read to the Society, Series IV
  - List of papers read to the Society (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Lucius E. Smith, A view of the ecclesiastical laws of New England from the foundation of the colonies to the final separation of church and state, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Henry S. Burrage, The beginnings of Waterville College, now Colby University, with a sketch of its first president, Rev. Jeremiah Chaplin, D.D., 1890 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - R.J. Adams, History of the Second Baptist Church of Holyoke, Massachusetts, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Henry M. King, The Baptists and religious liberty in this country, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - William H. Bowen, Six-Principle Baptists, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Alvah Hovey, Possessions of the Backus Historical Library, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Charles H. Watson, Chapin Howard Carpenter, 1835-1887, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - George E. Horr, Bits of Lay History, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Library, Series V
  - Catalogues
    - Catalogue, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Catalogue of pamphlets, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Accessions
    - Catalogue of Backus manuscripts obtained, 1830 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Accession list; list of items sold, 1904–1909 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Collected papers
    - Stephen Gano to Thomas Baldwin; from Providence, RI, 1806 December 19 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Lemuel Burkitt to [Thomas Baldwin]; from [Northampton], NC, 1807 July 21 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Stephen Gano to [Thomas Baldwin]; from Providence, RI, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Edmund Botsford, Autobiographical journal, 1809 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - John Leland, Autobiography, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Joseph Cornell to President and Trustees of Sturbridge Evangelical Baptist Missionary Society; from Sturbridge, 1813 March 2 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - M. Person, View of the aborginal Americans, 1813 March 2 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - M. Person, Brief view of the aboriginal Americans, 1813 March 12 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - M. Person, British influence, 1813 April 2 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - William Batchelder to James Duncan, 1815 February 16 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - W.H. Rowe to Isaac James; from Weymouth, MA, 1815 October 11 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Daniel Sharp to Irah Chase; from Boston, 1816 November 7 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Leonard Woods to Boston Baptist Association; from Andover, MA, 1817 September 15 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Daniel Sharp to Jonathan Smith; from Boston, 1818 July 24 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Thomas Baldwin to Jonathan Smith; from Boston, 1818 July 25 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Baptist Board of Foreign Missions for the United States to brethren of the Baptist denomination, 1818 August 10 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Samuel Eddy (for Brown University) to David Benedict; from Providence, RI, 1818 September 4 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Sentiments in the prospect of death supposed to be near (unknown hand; probably statements of Joseph Grafton), 1819 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Stephen Gano to Thomas Baldwin; from Providence, RI, 1819 March 22 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Pew deed for Daniel Alden--North Baptist Church, 1819 November 15 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Lucius Bolles (for Executive Committe of Baptist Education Society) to John Burleigh; from Salem, MA, 1819 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Elbridge Gale to Lucius Bolles; from Framingham, MA, 1820 October (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - ? to Jonathan Going; from Worcester, MA, 1821 March 12 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - William Staughton to D.B. Brown; from Philadelphia (I. Chase copy), 1821 October 29 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - William Staughton to Irah Chase; from Philadelphia, 1821 November 21 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - William Staughton to Irah Chase; from Philadelphia, 1821 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - J.M. Winchell to Irah Chase; from Boston, MA, 1822 September 22 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Account of Warren Baptist Association, 9/1821-4/1823, 1823 April 26 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Stephen Gano to E.B. Rogers; from Providence, RI, 1824 January 31 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Stephen Gano to Thomas Baldwin; from Providence, RI, 1824 March 10 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Daniel Sharp (for Third Baptist Church, Boston) to Boston Baptist Association, 1824 September 12 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Stephen Gano to Thomas Baldwin; from Providence, RI, 1825 February 18 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Daniel Sharp to Irah Chase; from Boston, 1825 August 22 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - David Wright to Jonathan Going; from Westfield, MA, 1825 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - E.C. Dyer (for the Board) to Baptist Education Society of the Young Men of Boston, 1825 December 10 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Thomas Rand to Jonathan Going; from Ware Factory Village, MA, 1825 December 27 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Stephen Gano to daughter Eliza; from Providence, RI, 1826 January (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - David James to Baptist Missionary Society of Massachusetts, 1827 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Salmon Ensign to Massachusetts Baptist Missionary Society; from Northampton, MA, 1827 May 31 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Extract of letter from Randolph, Pa (I. Chase description), 1827 November 20 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - William Spencer to Daniel Sharp; from Oxford, MA, 1827 November 21 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Peter Chase to Daniel Sharp; from Hinesburgh, VT, 1827 December 5 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Assessors of the town of Worcester to the Board of Overseers of the Centre School District in Worcester, 1828 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Ebenezer Poole, Jr. (for Gloucester Baptist Church and Society) to Daniel Sharp; from Gloucester, MA, 1828 January 7 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Eliab Going to Daniel Sharp; from Rushford, 1828 January 23 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - William Bruce (for Committee of Superintendence) to Daniel Sharp; from Bruceville, 1828 February 2 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Jacob Hatch to Daniel Sharp; from Dexter, ME, 1828 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Holland Turner to Lucius Bolles; from Rouses's Point, NY, 1828 February 11 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Samuel Glover to Daniel Sharp; from Boston, 1828 February 12 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Peter Chase to Daniel Sharp; from Hinesburgh, VT, 1828 February 13 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Jacob Hatch to Daniel Sharp; from Dexter, ME, 1828 February 21 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - William Spencer to Daniel Sharp; from Cincinnati, OH, 1828 March 6 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Squier Abbott to Daniel Sharp; from Henrietta, OH, 1828 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - John Haynes to Lucius Bolles; from Norway, NY, 1828 March 31 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Whitman Metcalf to Daniel Sharp; from Sardinia, NY, 1828 May 11 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - [Irah Chase] to Lincoln and Edmands; from Newton, MA, 1828 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Peter Chase to Daniel Sharp; from Hinesburgh, VT, 1828 May 15 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Joshua Eveleth to Jonathan Going; from Southbridge, MA, 1828 May 19 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Elijah Foster to Jonathan Going; from Amesbury, MA, 1828 May 19 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Peter Chase to Daniel Sharp; from Hinesburgh, VT, 1828 May 20 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Dunstable (NH) Baptist Church to Directors of Massachusetts Baptist Missionary Society, 1828 May 26 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Ebenezer Poole, Jr. (for Glouscester Baptist Church) to Board of Massachusetts Baptist Missionary Society, 1828 May 26 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - William Spencer to Daniel Sharp; from Oxford, MA, 1828 May 29 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - [Joseph Grafton] to E.W. Freeman, 1828 June 9 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Asa Bingham to Amos Bingham; from Camillus, NY, 1828 July 6 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - John Peak to Daniel Sharp; from Lynn, MA, 1828 July 12 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - J.L. Holman to Daniel Sharp; from Aurora, IN, 1828 July 28 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Holland Turner to Daniel Sharp; from Rouses Point, NY, 1828 August 12 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Williston Baptist Church, Certificate regarding ministry of P. Chase, 1828 September 1 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Peter Chase to Daniel Sharp; from Boston, 1828 September 15 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Simeon Crowell to Massachusetts Baptist Missionary Society; from South Yarmouth, MA, 1828 September 16 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Henry J. Hall to William Leverett; from Greenfield, IA, 1828 October 24 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - [Benjamin] Willard to Board of Massachusetts Baptist Convention; from Northampton, MA, 1828 Ocotber 30 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Winthrop Poole (for Gloucester Baptist Church and Society) to trustees of Board of Massachusetts Domestic Missions, 1828 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Simeon Crowell to Daniel Sharp; from South Yarmouth, MA, 1828 December 29 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Eliab Going to Daniel Sharp; from Rushford, 1829 January 26 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Benjamin Oviatt to Ensign Lincoln; from Smithport, 1829 January 29 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Thomas Rand to Jonathan Going; from New Salem, MA, 1829 February 4 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - John Spalding to trustees of Massachusetts Baptist Missionary Society; from Franklin, MA, 1829 April 3 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Jonathan Blake to Ensign Lincoln; from Randolph, MA, 1829 April 10 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Eliab Going to Daniel Sharp; from --, 1829 May 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Peter Chase to Daniel Sharp; from Williston, VT, 1829 May 23 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The objects of Williston Academy (letter to editor of Spectator), 1829 June 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Peter Chase to Howard Malcom; from Williston, VT, 1829 June 12 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - John Peak to Daniel Sharp; from South Reading, MA, 1829 July 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - B.F. Edwards to Heman Lincoln; from Edwardsville, IL, 1829 July 8 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Thomas Marshall to C.P. Grosvenor; from Petersham, MA, 1829 July 8 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Asa Averill to Howard Malcom; from Woodsville, NH?, 1829 October 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Ezra Going to Jonathan Going; from Wayne, 1829 October 21 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - John Spalding to Howard Malcom; from Franklin, MA, 1829 November 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Jonathan Blake to Daniel Sharp; from Randolph, MA, 1829 December 8 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Peter Chase to Howard Malcom; from Newton, MA, 1829 December 31 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Thomas Marshall to Howard Malcom; from Petersham, MA, 1830 January 7 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - William Sedgwick to Howard Malcom; from Zanesville, OH, 1830 January 9 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Samuel Wait to Howard Malcom; from Newbern, NC, 1830 January 20 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Seth Ewer to Howard Malcom; from Attleboro, MA, 1830 February 4 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - John T. Moses to Howard Malcom; from Exeter, NH (incomplete), 1830 February 10 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Hubbel Loomis to Lucius Bolles; from East Dudley, MA, 1830 February 17 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - John T. Moses to Daniel Sharp; from Exeter, NH, 1830 March 4 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Seth Ewer to Jonathan Going; from Taunton, MA, 1830 March 6 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Isaac Kimball to Jonathan Going; from Wallingford, CT, 1830 March 7 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Solomon Peck to Howard Malcom; from Amherst, MA, 1830 March 7 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - B.L. Chambers to R.M. Johnson; from Georgetown, KY, 1830 March 8 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - John Spalding to Howard Malcom; from Franklin, MA, 1830 March 26 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - William Sedgwick to Howard Malcom; from Zanesville, OH, 1830 April 15 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Samuel Wait to Howard Malcom; from Newbern, NC, 1830 Arpil 24 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Ezra Going to Jonathan Going; from Buckland, MA, 1830 April 26 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Stephen Pillsbury to Howard Malcom; from Hebron, NH, 1830 May 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - E.W. Freeman to Jonathan Going; from Lowell, MA, 1830 May 17 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - [Joseph Grafton] to ?; from Newton, MA, 1830 June 9 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - William Sedgwick to Howard Malcom; from Zanesville, OH, 1830 June 11 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Charles Train to Jonathan Going; from Framingham, MA, 1830 June 18 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Elias Megregory to Jonathan Going; from North Leverett, MA, 1830 June 30 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - ? to Jonathan Going; from Newton, MA, 1830 July 23 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - J. Greene to Jonathan Going; from Sturbridge, MA, 1830 August 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Samuel Wait to Howard Malcom; from Newbern, NC, 1830 August 3 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - D. Wright to Jonathan Going; from Cummington, MA, 1830 August 3 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Hanover Baptist Society to Jonathan Going; from Hanover, MA, 1830 August 4 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - B.F. Remington to Jonathan Going; from Savoy, MA, 1830 August 13 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - [Benjamin] Willard to Jonathan Going; from Northampton, MA, 1830 August 25 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Certificate regarding completion of course of study at Newton Theological Institution for Jeremiah Hall, 1830 September 9 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - J_ Greene to Jonathan Going; from Leicester, MA, 1830 October 18 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Gideon B. Perry to Jonathan Going; from New Bedford, MA, 1830 October 22 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - William Hubbard to Jonathan Going; from Middleboro, MA, 1830 December 7 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Horace Hunt to Jonathan Going; from New Salem, MA, 1830 December 11 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Quincy Hersy to Jonathan Going; from Hingham, MA, 1830 December 27 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - William Sedgwick to William Leverett; from --, 1830 December 31 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - B.F. Remington to Jonathan Going; from Leyden, MA, 1831 March 12 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Nicholas Branch to Jonathan Going; from Springfield, MA, 1831 March 12 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - John Booth to Howard Malcom; from Troy, MI, 1831 March 17 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Hubbel Loomis to William Leverett; from Kaskaskia, IL, 1831 April 1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Joseph R. John to Heman Lincoln; from Troy, OH, 1831 April 11 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Board of Managers of Rhode Island Baptist Convention, Request to Massachusetts Domestic Missionary Society for financial aid, 1831 May 20 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Elisha Andrews to Board of Trustees of Massachusetts Baptist Missionary Society; from Boston, MA, 1831 May 26 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Elisha Andrews to Heman Lincoln; from Boston, MA, 1831 May 27 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - [Joseph Grafton] to ?; from Newton, MA, 1831 June 9 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Whitman Metcalf to Board of Baptist Missionary Society of Massachusetts; from Sardinia, NY, 1831 July 6 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Franklinsville (NY), Farmersville (NY) and Freedom (NY) Baptist churches to Massachusetts Horne Missionary Board, 1831 July 7 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - John Booth to William Leverett; from Troy, MI, 1831 July 9 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Jonathan Blake to Secretary of Massachusetts Baptist Convention; from Sardinia, OH, 1831 July 17 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Peter Chase to William Leverett; from Franklin, MA, 1831 July 27 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Hubbel Loomis (et al.) for Corresponding Committee of the Union Meeting of Baptists in Illinois to William Leverett; from Kaskaskia, IL, 1831 August 22 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Hubbel Loomis to William Leverett; from Kaskaskia, IL, 1831 August 23 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Joseph R. John to William Leverett; from Troy, OH, 1831 September 5 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Leland Howard, Certificate regarding church membership of Sewall S. Cutting, Windsor, VT, 1831 September 6 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - M. Fairfield to Lucius Bolles; from Troy, OH, 1831 September 11 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - H.J. Hall to William Leverett; from Cornwall, VT, 1831 October 7 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Watertown Baptist Church to Trustees of Massachusetts Baptist Missionary Society, 1831 November 6 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - John Booth to William Leverett; from Troy, MI, 1831 December 16 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - H.J. Hall to William Leverett; from Cornwall, VT, 1831 December 24 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - William Sedgwick to William Leverett; from Zanesville, OH, 1831 December 26 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Willard Kimball to Heman Lincoln; from East Bethel, VT, 1831 December 28 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Micaiah Fairfield to William Leverett; from Troy, OH, 1832 February 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Lucas Austin to Jonathan Going; from Holland, MI, 1832 February 7 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Willard Kimball to William Leverett; from East Bethel, VT, 1832 February 20 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Appleton Morse to Abial Fisher; from Princeton, MA, 1832 March 21 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Gay Head, Martha's Vineyard Baptist Church to Secretary of Massachusetts Baptist Missionary Convention (also includes 5/13/1832 and 5/15/1832 documents), 1832 March 25 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Gloucester First Baptist Church to Board of Massachusetts Baptist Convention, 1832 April 28 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - New Bedford First Baptist Church to Abial Fisher, 1832 May 7 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Holmes Hole Baptist Church to Massachusetts Baptist Missionary Convention (with 3/25/1832 document and filed in that chronology), 1832 May 13 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Edgartown, Martha's Vineyard Baptist Church to Massachusetts Baptist Missionary Convention (with 3/25/1832 document and filed in that chronology), 1832 May 15 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Elisha Andrews to William Leverett; from Hinsdale, MA, 1832 May 29 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - [Joseph Grafton], Autobiographical statement, 1832 June 9 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Levi Pierce to Abial Fisher; from Middleboro, MA, 1832 June 15 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Benjamin Willard to Abial Fisher; from Northampton, MA (includes 10/25/1832 postscript), 1832 July 26 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Luther Hunt to Board of Massachusetts Baptist Convention; from New Salem, MA, 1832 July 29 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Eliab Going to William Leverett; from Rushford, 1832 September 5 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Joseph Grafton to John Stanford; from Newton, MA, 1833 April 11 (Box 3, Folder 20)